Elijah Blaisdell

Seattle, WA

206-225-1482

elijahblaisdell@gmail.com LinkedIn: <u>/elijahblaisdell</u> GitHub: <u>/elijah415hz</u>

Portfolio: elijah415hz.herokuapp.com

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer and international classical musician with a deep understanding of effective team collaboration. Skilled and persistent problem solver who writes clean, elegant code. A passionate craftsman and creative thinker committed to doing things right the first time, whenever possible. Very quick study, accustomed to performing under pressure, and experienced in adapting to client requests.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, NoSQL

Applications: Github, MongoDB, MySQL

Tools: Node, Express, React, Handlebars, ¡Query, Bootstrap, Flask, Pandas, Matplotlib

EDUCATION

UW Coding Bootcamp in Full Stack Web Development

Master of Music in Vocal Performance, New England Conservatory

Bachelor of Music in Vocal Performance, Central Washington University, Magna Cum Laude

PROJECTS

Cfe-app | github.com/dan-gentile/coffee-app-client | cfe-client.herokuapp.com/

- Cfe is a React browser app that allows the user to search for good coffee through a curated map search.
- The repo above is for the client facing part of the application. Links to the server and admin dashboard are in the client repo
- SCSS, JavaScript, React, Mongoose, Google Sign In, JSON web tokens

We-patch | github.com/elijah415hz/we-patch | we-patch.herokuapp.com

- A full-stack web application to connect people looking for gardening space to people who have space they'd like to share. Built using Leaflet.js, bcrypt, Nodemailer, and Cloudinary.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Foundation, Sequelize, Handlebars, Express-Sessions

Flask of Finances | github.com/elijah415hz/finances-flask

- A deep dive into Typescript and Flask, this is an ongoing project to help me manage my finances.
- Built so my family could have a fully customizable way to track and analyze our finances. Not publicly deployed as it interacts with my personal data.
- React, Typescript, Python, Flask, Pandas, Matplotlib, MySQL, Google Cloud, Apps Scripts, JSON web tokens

EXPERIENCE

Freelance classical singer | New York City, 2014-2020 | www.elijahblaisdell.com

- 2018 Grammy-award winner with The Crossing
- Managed multiple, simultaneous collaborative projects in different genres and languages (German, Italian, French, Swedish)
- Coordinated and adapted efficiently (and often wordlessly) in new environments with unfamiliar colleagues
- Balanced a busy performing schedule, negotiated contracts, and organized travel/expenses

Group Educator & Facilitator | Western Wind Ensemble | New York City, 2019-2020

• Facilitated small group amateur music ensembles and led large group vocal workshops

Shift Manager | Starbucks | Boston, 2014-2015

- Managed a small team of baristas to optimize efficiency and customer satisfaction
- Oversaw inventory in collaboration with a team of managers and trained new employees

Project Lead | Alternative Technology Resource Center (ATRC) at CWU | Ellensburg, 2011-12

- Produced translations of alternative media textbooks including human read audio, PC audio, and math braille for learning disabled and visually impaired students
- Experience with Microsoft Word, Excel and Microsoft Word macros